KSHENIN ALEXANDER

24 years, Saint Petersburg Data Scientist, Machine Learning engineer Remote work is possible



CONTACTS

****+7 (911) 783-09-44

■ alexander.kshenin@gmail.com

https://github.com/AlexKornShell

COVERING COMMENT

After finishing my project for NCCR I took a break from work. I engage in self-education: recently studied PyTorch, expanded my knowledge in deep learning methods and models. Confident with Python and general DS knowledge stack (*Scikit-learn, pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib*, etc.), possess an advanced mathematical background, public speaking skills, work experience with SQL, Git, REST API, Java, C++, deep learning libraries. I am ready to grow in new areas and scope of application of machine learning, data analysis, modeling. Quickly master technologies and tools.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineer | **ITMO** University National Center for Cognitive Research | 10.2019 – 06.2021

- Main projects:
 - Development of a predictive model of therapy for patients with arterial hypertension (using anamnesis data)
 - Building a map of points of interest in St. Petersburg based on Instagram posts
 - Preparation of a library for business process models construction
 - Simulation modeling and analysis of business processes in medical center
- Tasks (and technologies): web scraping (*Beautiful Soup*), data preprocessing and analysis (*pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib*), predictive modeling (*Scikit-learn, xgboost*), text processing, topic modeling (*NLTK, BigARTM*), testing (*unittest*), design of algorithms (*Python 3*), simulation modeling (*SimPy*), sensitivity analysis (*SALib*)
- Defense of research at conferences: pHealth (November 2021), X Congress of Young Scientists (April 2021), MICSECS-2020 (December 2020), and others
- I have a publication in the Procedia Computer Science, Studies in Health Technology and Informatics, in ITMO University collection of works of young scientists, in several conferences' proceedings
- Continued my research till November 2021, finishing with pHealth international conference and publication

Intern ITMO University Digital Healthcare Lab

08.2019 - 10.2019

• Acquaintance with the department, the beginning of work on projects

Technician | ITMO University Faculty of Control Systems and Robotics

12.2018 - 06.2019

- Conducting a seminar on mathematical foundations of robotics under a faculty grant
- Defense of a research

Intern | Implementation department of OpenWay Service

07.2018 - 08.2018

- Summer school internship. Creating a QR-code payment service based on the company's products
- My main tasks: Implementation of a mobile application (*Ionic Framework*), part of the server component (*Java*), Rest API for interaction with the system

EDUCATION

Master's degree

ITMO University, Faculty of Digital Transformation, Mathematical modeling in medicine and healthcare

2019 - 2021

- Diploma with honors
- Studied machine learning algorithms, neural networks (*Keras, TensorFlow*), discrete and continuous models (*SciPy, SimPy*), methods and models for multivariate data analysis, time series (*ARIMA*), evolutionally algorithms (*deap*), parallel algorithms of data analysis (*OpenMP, CUDA*), as well as applications in medical and healthcare tasks
- Training team projects:
 - Analysis of topic dynamics in tweets about coronavirus in March–April 2020, search for hidden states of discussion (*BigARTM*, *ARIMA*, *Scikit-learn*)
 - Development of health information system, divided among students into a set of services (*Django*, *PostgreSQL*)

Bachelor's degree

ITMO University, Faculty of Control Systems and Robotics, Mathematical modeling

2015 - 2019

- Diploma with honors
- Studied advanced mathematics (advanced courses in algebra, geometry, statistics, etc.), algorithms and data structures, OOP (*Java*), databases (*SQL*), optimization methods, computing software (*Mathcad*, *MATLAB*, *Mathematica*)
- Participated in quantum optics seminars in 2017–2018. Worked on the problem of modeling an optical signal in a turbulent atmosphere

ABOUT ME

- English Advanced (C1)
- 2019–2021 V. Potanin Foundation Fellow
- Received a government scholarship for priority areas in 2020